Welcome to the video on how to improve apparel and shoe detail pages to reduce returns.
Product
returns are a part of the shopping experience in fashion.
As a result, they can have a significant
impact on customers trust in you as an Amazon selling partner.
This video will summarize
best practices to reduce customer returns of apparel and shoes.
Follow this simple step
of reviewing and updating offer attributes.
Now it's time to review your existing detail
page attributes.
To improve your existing listing attributes, click on the take action
button and select edit listing.
You will be routed to the listing page five seconds after
you select edit listing where you can begin updating and improving your existing listing
attributes.
First, confirm that your listing has sizing options that are accurate and local
to the US.
This is important for both consistency and the customer experience and to help products
be more discoverable via search.
Sizes should be listed in an ascending order from smallest
to largest.
Add additional details for body and height types such as big or tall so customers
have a better understanding of sizing and can choose apparel that fits.
To reduce confusion,
Amazon has recently updated the size field to a standardized format.
Fill in the corresponding
required attributes for your product, which will then be automatically combined in a customer-friendly
format on the display page.
Next, check if your title is accurate and compliant.
Titles
are critical in both catching a customer's attention and helping identify products through
Amazon search.
Titles should be concise, informative and accurate.
In general, they include brand
product type and other identifying information.
Titles should not be used to include promotional
information.
Titles should follow the category-specific Amazon syntax.
In addition, titles of product
variants such as size and color should appear on the detail page.
Now let's learn about product
images.
It's crucial to include multiple high-quality images to provide as much clarity to the
customer as possible.
It is recommended that each detail page includes 5 to 7 images.
Please
remember that images should have an all-white background.
Include images that show the product
from multiple angles, detail shots of key features and wherever possible be on model.
Using multiple
models and images can help customers better envision the garment on a variety of body types.
Keep in mind that for ASINs that are shared across countries, images will be shared as well.
Please ensure that for these ASINs, images are applicable to all countries.
We recommend
including measurement information in both inches and centimeters to address all locations.
Product descriptions and bullet points should be used to provide the customer with additional fit,
material and product care information not easily conveyed through images.
Whenever possible,
include the following in bullet points.
One, if the product runs large or small.
Two, the model's
measurements and the corresponding garment size.
Three, specific product measurements.
For example,
inseam length or waist size.
Four, styling information such as tight fitting or off the shoulder.
To
provide a better customer experience, the bullet points in some categories are pulled directly from
ASIN data.
In shoes, and clothing for example, attributes like material, heel height or sleeve
type are automatically included to provide customers additional fit information.
Size charts are one
of the most helpful components of detail pages for customers who have sizing questions.
Size chart
data should include specific body measurements aligned to their corresponding garment size.
Reach out to seller support to upload your brand specific size chart.
Size chart widget data is
automatically shown on product detail pages for all ASINs in the applicable Amazon store that
share the same brand name, department name and product type.
Ensure that these values match those
included in the size selection drop down.
Confirm that all ASINs contain complete and valid attributes
else the size chart will not be displayed.
A+ content is not only a great place to advertise
your brand but also a fantastic resource for proactively answering customer questions.
For
example, some brands use a+ content to describe different fit types available with their product.
Another option is to provide styling information such as images of the various ways the product
can be worn.
Thank you for taking this training on product detail page best practices.
Please remember
to rate and review this video so that we can continue building useful content.